appannie.com 2013-11-02

# Privacy Policy | App Annie

App Annie has been awarded TRUSTe’s Privacy Seal signifying that this Privacy Policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe’s program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability, and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. If you have questions or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy or practices, please contact us. If you are not satisfied with our response, you can [contact TRUSTe](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

App Annie Limited knows that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. By using the [www.AppAnnie.com](http://www.appannie.com/) website (the “Site”) and/or any of our applications (such as our iPhone application) (together with the Site, the “Service”) you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this privacy policy (“Policy”).

This Policy describes how App Annie collects and uses the personal information you provide on the Service (or that we otherwise collect in connection with the Service) as well as the data we collect by connecting to third party sources on your behalf as authorized by you (and described further below). - It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of such information and how you can access and update this information. This Policy is in effect throughout the full duration of your use of the Site and Service. If you do not agree to this Policy, you are not permitted to use the Site or Services. You are responsible for regularly reviewing this Policy and updates to it. Please review it carefully. Any capitalized terms used herein without definition shall have the meaning given to them in our Terms of Service.

Please understand that your privacy and the security of your data is our primary concern.

App Annie has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, [www.appannie.com](http://www.appannie.com/).

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

“App Annie Analytics”: the specific section of our Service where our users maintain their Source Accounts Information and access the Collected Data. We present your data visually in charts as part of the Service for App Annie Analytics, unless you request that we give you access to your Collected Data in raw data format (through downloadable files or API). 

“Collected Data”: data collected by us by either connecting to the Sources on behalf of our users or accessing uploaded data (through manual data entry, uploaded files, API, or any other means) from our users to our Site. Collected Data does not include public data already directly available via the Sources. An example of Collected Data is an iTunes Sales Report.

“Source Account Information”: your user login and password information for access to your data from a specific Source, for example, your iTunes Connect user name and password.

“Sources”: online third-party data web sites, which may include, without limitation, Apple iTunes Connect, Google Play and other app stores, digital distribution, analytics and advertising and monetization platforms.

We collect the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail, aggregate information on what pages users access or visit, and information volunteered by the user (such as survey information and/or site registrations).

In the course of using our site or registering for the Services, we may collect contact Information such as:

  * Name, mailing address, phone number, job function, job role
  * Unique identifiers such as user name, account number, password
  * Information about your business such as company name, company size, and business type.

We use this information to:

  * Send you a registration confirmation
  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Contact you for marketing and sales purposes to provide you with more information about our products
  * Improve our Site and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis
  * Match you to other web services to provide a more customized experience for you. For example, but without limitation, pulling user photos from linkedin or gravatar, or potentially integrating with FB connect.

In addition, our mobile application will collect and track information regarding the mobile experience - such as your phone model, the duration and frequency of your usage sessions, information regarding application crashes, the particular screens you choose to view, etc.

While using App Annie Analytics, we will also store our user’s Source Account Information and gather Collected Data. This data is stored inline with our Data Security Policy. Your Source Account Information and the Collected Data is used primarily in App Annie Analytics: obtaining and presenting to you your own downloads, sales, advertising, and analytics reports. We also use Collected Data as part of the Service when you decide to share your Collected Data with other users of the Service. We also use Collected Data in our App Annie Statistical Model, how we use this data is detailed in the section called “Ownership and Privacy of Data”. 

We use cookies to track your session information in order to improve your experience of the Site and the quality of our Service. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We do link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our site. 

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. An example of how we use session cookies is to remember if you have a closed a notification message on one page, so that we don’t show it to you again. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. An example of how we use persistent cookies is to remember that you have already authenticated with the Site, and to not require you to log in again when returning to the Site. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. You can learn more about cookies [here](http://www.google.com/goodtoknow/manage-data/cookies/). If you reject cookies, you may still use the Site, but your ability to use some areas of the Site will be limited

We employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers’ personal information.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information.

The use of tracking technologies by our technology partners and other 3rd party assets on the site is not covered by our privacy policy. These 3rd parties may use cookies, clear gifs, images, and scripts to help them better manage content on our site. We do not have access or control over these technologies.

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personally-identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to register. If you are under 13, please do not attempt to register for the Site or Services. In the event that we learn that we have collected personally identifiable information from a child under age 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at [support@appannie.com](mailto:support@appannie.com).

To further protect your Source security, we advise you to, where applicable and depending on the Sources, limit our access rights for App Annie Analytics by creating and using a separated account with limited roles. See our FAQ and your Sources documentation on how to set this up.

While using App Annie Analytics, all data that is transferred between your computer and our Service is encrypted with Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

You are only authorized to use App Annie Analytics to retrieve information which you have lawful rights to access and provide to us, per the Rights You Grant Us in our Terms of Services

While using the Service, we never store your sensitive information in cookies.

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. We have a Security Policy that details how App Annie transmits, stores and uses Collected Data.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [support@appannie.com](mailto:support@appannie.com).

We understand that the use of App Annie Analytics requires sensitive statistical and financial data to be stored on our servers, and that steps must be taken to ensure this data stays private.

Except as described herein, your specific set of Collected Data will never be disclosed, sold or shared with a third party in an identifiable and non-anonymous form, unless we conclude that it is required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, or to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

We may also choose to buy or sell assets, and in these types of transactions, data is typically one of the transferred assets. If App Annie is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

To market, operate and improve our services for you and other customers (including our App Annie Intelligence service), and build and operate new services and products, we reserve the right, and you hereby grant us a non-exclusive, worldwide, royalty-free, perpetual, irrevocable, sublicensable and transferable (as set forth in this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms of Use) right, to use your Collected Data for such purposes. 

Specifically, we will periodically access and include your Collected Data in the pool of data used by our App Annie Statistical Model to generate and provide estimates of app performance (e.g., downloads, revenues, etc) across publishers, industries, geographies and marketplaces. Subscribers to our App Annie Intelligence service will never receive your specific set of Collected Data in an identifiable, non-aggregated form. You hereby acknowledge and consent to such use by using our Service. 

For the avoidance of doubt, the estimates generated by our App Annie Statistical Model (and made available to others) may include performance estimates of your apps that are derived from pools of information including your Collected Data. Because they are generated by our Statistical Model from pooled information and are only estimates, we consider these estimates regarding your apps to be non-identifiable, aggregated and anonymized even though (a) the estimates may be very similar to the actual performance data you provided as part of the Collected Data and (b) the estimates may specifically name each app and publisher.

Additionally, from time to time, our sales, support and engineering staff (including those of third party service providers we use authorized to carry out tasks on our behalf as described below) may log in to the Service on your account in order to provide you assistance with sales, billing or technical issues upon your request. 

Furthermore, all employees of App Annie are required to sign an Insider Trading Policy agreement and Non-Disclosure Agreement to ensure the privacy of your Collected Data and Source Account Information.

Information is also provided in certain limited circumstances to third parties to carry out tasks on our behalf for the purpose of maintaining, operating, providing and improving the Service (including without limitation, billing, emailing, processing applications, CRM, support or data storage) with strict restrictions that prevent the data from being used or shared except as directed by us. When third parties are carrying out these tasks on our behalf, they are subject to agreements that oblige them to process such information only on our instructions and in compliance with this Policy and to undertake appropriate confidentiality and security measures. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. You hereby acknowledge and consent to such use by using our Service.

Some of our pages (such as those accepting job applications) utilize framing techniques to serve content from our partners while preserving the look and feel of our site. Please be aware that you are providing your personal information to these third parties and not to App Annie.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete or remove your information through your Account Settings page, by emailing our Customer Support at [support@appannie.com](mailto:support@appannie.com) or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

We will delete your account and associated account information (such as your contact details, email addresses and Source Account Information) upon your request. While we will immediately cease collection of your Collected Data upon deletion of your account, any of your previously Collected Data that has already been included in the pool of data used by our App Annie Statistical Model will not be deleted.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us at [support@appannie.com](mailto:support@appannie.com).

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of App Annie. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

We may display personal testimonials of satisfied users or customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [support@appannie.com](mailto:support@appannie.com).

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum contact us at [support@appannie.com](mailto:support@appannie.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, the “Share this” button or other interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

App Annie reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to modify this policy at any time, effective by posting new policy on the Site with the date of modification. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. You are responsible for reading and understanding the terms of this policy prior to using the Service. Your use of the Site or Service after any such modification has been published constitutes your acceptance of the privacy policy as modified in this policy.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding anything in this Policy, please contact us. Our address is as follows:

App Annie Limited  
35/F Central Plaza  
18 Harbour Road  
Wan Chai, Hong Kong
